## **Alexander Leakos**

Calgary AB, Canada · (403) 921-1061 · aleakos@gmail.com · github.com/aleakos

## **SUMMARY**

Software Developer with 2+ years of experience leading the design, development, and deployment of full stack eCommerce solutions. Focused on working with teams solving complex problems for high performance, user-focused platforms that unlock efficiency and productivity for customers at scale.

#### **SKILLS**

- Engineering: Product Roadmap, Frontend & UI/UX, Backend & Infrastructure, Cloud Architecture, API Development & Integration, RESTful Web Services, Microservices, Software Design & Coding, Testing & Code Coverage, Software Quality, Scalability, Performance, Reliability, Automation, Code Reviews, Documentation
- Leadership: Strategic Planning & Execution, Project Management, Prioritization, Process Improvement, Cross-functional Collaboration, Staff Hiring & Management, Training & Development, Coaching & Mentorship, Interdepartmental Alignment, Change Management, Business Development, Financial Modeling & Analysis, Budgeting & Resource Allocation, Reporting
- Software: Python, PySpark, Java, Javascript, React, Databricks, C/C++, SQL, Graph QL, Excel/VBA, RDBMS (Postgres/MySQL)

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

• Master of Science in Software Engineering, University of Calgary

Expected 2022

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, University of Calgary

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

### Co-Founder/Software Developer/Operations & Finance Manager, Bessie Box

2019 - 2021

- Grew a local grocery eCommerce brand from \$0 to \$750K in annualized revenue with a 4-person team.
- Sourced products from 12 local farms and producers and coordinated shipping, receiving, and distribution for 3K customers.
- Automated SMS communications for subscription delivery scheduling, follow-up feedback, and marketing with historical data using Slack, Twilio, and Shopify APIs to optimize courier routing, enable order/delivery batching, & streamline delivery.
- Managed a Digital Ocean server, using Nginx and Gunicorn for load balancing, and built a PostgreSQL database to implement new eCommerce applications from the ground up, serving hundreds of concurrent users.
- Designed and created frontends and dashboards for internal apps using Retool, a low code tool that allows non-technical users and marketing teams to interact with customers and product data and utilize the functionality of internal APIs.
- Maintained 30%+ gross margins by analyzing and negotiating the cost of products, couriers, packaging, and labor.
- Integrated internal apps with 4 other Shopify store owners to streamline inventory management and communications.
- Updated the inventory database automatically to maintain accurate inventory levels using Shopify webhooks and implemented complex backend logic for product bundles not available in Shopify natively.

# **Analyst, Roynat Equity Partners**

2017 - 2019

- Analyzed financial statements and prepared financial models of prospective and current investments for a team deploying \$300MM in capital across a wide array of industries resulting in 6 investments and 8 divestments.
- Created investment presentations to internally market deals, present business cases for investments, and secure funding.
- Evaluated existing portfolios against industry standards using financial modeling to measure and guide current performance and preemptively identify the need for potential exit strategies.

### Research Associate, Avrio Capital

2016 - 2017

• Conducted due diligence for a VC firm with a \$200MM fund. Produced research, reports, and models for the fund to evaluate assets within emerging and existing agricultural markets, leading to acquisitions and divestments.

# Operations Engineering Intern, Paramount Resources Ltd.

2014 - 2015

- Coordinated work-overs for 100+ oil wells to ensure on-time repairs and optimize performance.
- Performed an economic evaluation of a 30 well field to determine site viability based on current & forecasted market prices.
- Developed a database for 300+ wells to ensure compliance with new AER guidelines for suspended and abandoned wells.
- Analyzed wellbores and identified a necessary tubing change that reduced shut-in time by 25% and increased profitability.